Let me now quickly, show you some of the stuff,
that we just learned and practice.
And so let's not build an extremely simple example.
So I will start by simply logging test, start
to the console.
Then, afterwards I will create a set time out,
with something that will just also lock something
to the console only.
So zero second timer.
And so that's because we will fire this timer
after exactly zero seconds.
Okay.
So basically this is a timer,
which should call this timer function exactly
after zero seconds.
So what that means is that after zero seconds,
this callback will be put on the callback queue, right?
Then next up, let's build a promise
that resolves immediately.
So this is something that we will learn
in the next video actually.
And so for now, just follow what I'm writing here.
So promise that resolve, basically allows us
to build a promise, so to create a promise
that is immediately resolved.
So one that immediately has a success value.
And so that fulfilled, success value, is gonna be this one
we passed in here.
So resolved, promise, one,
and then we can handle that resolved promise.
And so that, our response we can then simply log it
to the console.
So, just like in any other promise,
we can handle it with a den method.
And this callback function here, will get called with the
resolved value, as an argument.
And so in this case,
the result value of that promise, is this one here that we
just specified.
And now just to finish, let's just log another string test.
And, and so for now, that's actually it.
So in what order do you think that these four messages,
that we have here, will be logged to the console?
And I want you to really think about this and maybe even
pause the video, and write it down.
Well, let's think about this together
before we actually check out the result.
So the first two messages that are gonna be printed
should be pretty obvious,
that's because we already know that any top level of coat.
So coat outside of any callback, will run first.
And so of course, the first two logs will come
from these two synchronous, console dot log Sierra.
But now between the timer, and the resolved promise here,
it might be a little bit trickier.
So both the timer and a promise,
will finish at the exact same time.
So both right after zero seconds.
So the timer,
because we told it to finish after zero seconds
and a promise because we told it to immediately
become resolved.
Right?
And so therefore,
they will both finish at the exact same time.
So which one do you think will be handled first
or in other words,
which of these two callbacks here will be executed first?
Well, the timer appears first in the coat
and so it kind of finished first.
And so it's callback,
will be put on the callback queue first, but does that mean
that this call back here will be executed first?
Well, actually, no, it doesn't.
And that's because of the micro-tasks queue, remember?
So the callback of the resolved promise here,
so this one will be put on the micro-tasks queue and this
micro-tasks queue, as you learned in the last video
has priority over the callback queue.
And so after this whole code runs,
we will have one callback in a callback queue
and one in a micro-tasks queue.
And therefore the one from the micro tests queue
should be executed first.
And so therefore the callback from the micro-tasks queue
And so that's this one here and there for the first message
to appear of these two, should be resolved Promise one.
All right.
So the order in which they should appear
is this tenders, tenders and finally the timer.
And so that's now finally confirmed as, so I'm saving it
and indeed did as exactly as expected.
And so that's a relief actually.
So what I told you in the last lecture is actually true.
Now we proved it with coat.
Now, remember that the implication
of the fact that micro-tasks have priority
over regular callbacks, is that if one of
the micro-tasks takes a long time to run,
then the timer will actually be delayed and not run after
the zero seconds that we specified here, right?
So instead it will run a little bit later just after
the micro-task is actually done with its work.
And so to finish this lecture,
let's actually simulate what I just said.
So here I will create another promise,
that will immediately resolve.
So let's just say resolved promise two, and then again,
we can handle it here.
And then as always, we want to log,
the result to the console.
But before we doing that,
we actually want this callback function
to have a really heavy task,
which should take a lot of time.
And so let's simulate that this callback takes a long time
to run, by looping over a large number.
So we can do the simulation simply,
with an old school four loop.
So let's start with I at zero and now I will loop
all the way until one like very large number.
Let's say this, and I will have to experiment a little bit.
And for your computer, it might indeed be different.
So if your computer is slower,
maybe then you want a smaller number
and maybe it's faster than mine.
And then maybe a smaller number will be enough, right?
I'm not sure if I said it correctly.
So if your computer is slower than mine,
then you will need a larger number, right?
And so again, this line of code here will simulate
that the callback function takes a long time.
So really just this micro-task takes a long time.
All right, it is not the asynchronous task itself.
So the promise itself will still be resolved immediately,
but then the micro-task that it contains,
so that it puts on the micro-tasks queue.
That's the one that will take a long time.
And so by doing that,
I can show you that the callbacks in the callback queue,
just like this one here, will indeed be delayed
and not run after zero seconds.
So let's try this now,
and you see it took a long time here
until this lock appeared, right?
So maybe we can have even a bigger number.
And I hope that my computer is not going to explode,
with this one.
So you see that the page is kind of loading here
and it's taking a lot of time.
And so, actually now eventually it finished,
but you see, that now only after all this work,
the zero second timer message appeared on the screen.
And so this is actual proof that these zero seconds
that we have here are not a guarantee.
Okay.
And that is exactly what I wanted to show you.
So this means, that you cannot really do high precision
things using JavaScript timers.
So just keep that in mind,
whenever you are working with promises.
So basically with micro-tasks,
and with timers at the same time.
Okay.
Let's just remove the zero here,
so that you don't explode your computer,
but you still see that the effect is the same.
All right, and that's actually enough for this video.
I think I proved my point and demonstrated to the things
that we just learned in the previous lecture.
And so now we're ready to go back to some more practical
aspects of asynchronous JavaScript, and that will be
to create promises from scratch in the next video.